bedsider.org 2017-01-29

# Privacy Policy - Bedsider

Welcome to Bedsider.org and the Bedsider network (collectively, “Bedsider”). Bedsider is operated by The National Campaign to Prevent Teen and Unplanned Pregnancy (“The National Campaign,” “we,” or “us”). 

This page lists all the privacy stuff you need to know. There’s a lot of text, so here’s the summary: Your privacy is important to us. We’ll never sell your name or information. Ever. But there may be times we share it with our partners if they’re providing a service to you. 

### Information we collect

_Personal Information._ We may collect and store any information that you choose to enter through Bedsider. This includes personal information, such as your name, e-mail address, telephone number, zip code, and date of birth, and other information (personal and non-personal) about you that you may submit through Bedsider, including through any content that you provide. We may require that you provide some personal information in order to participate in certain features we offer. In some cases, we may combine this information with personal information we have collected about you from other sources.

_Automatic Information._ We may automatically collect some information about your computer when you visit Bedsider.org. For example, we may collect your IP address, Web browser software (such as Internet Explorer), and referring web site. We also may collect information about your activity on Bedsider. We may combine this automatically-gathered information with other information, including personal information we have collected about you.

_Cookies_. When you visit Bedsider, we may assign your computer a “cookie” (a small, unique identifier text file) to remember who you are. We also may include other information in our cookie files; for example, if you arrived at Bedsider via a link from a third-party site, we may include the URL of the linking page. In addition, we collect gender, age, and interest information from 3rd parties using Google Analytics. We may combine the information we collect through cookies with other information, including personal information we have gathered about your visit in aggregate to improve our services.

### How we use this information

We may use the information we collect about you in certain ways in connection with our business. These uses include:

  * Providing you with the products and services you request;
  * Responding to your questions and comments; 
  * Providing you with information, including advertising, about selected products and services offered by Bedsider or others that may be of interest to you;
  * Facilitating communications between you, your friends, and other users;
  * Soliciting information and feedback from you, including through surveys and questionnaires;
  * Performing business analyses or for other purposes to improve the quality of our business, and the products and services we offer; and
  * As otherwise described to you at the point of collection or pursuant to your consent.  

### With whom we share this information

We may share the information we collect about you in limited circumstances, including:

  * With our authorized service providers that perform certain functions or services on our behalf (such as to transmit communications or advertising, or assist with the transactions you initiate), although we require that these third parties limit their use of your personal information to providing the service for which the information was shared;
  * To affiliates within the Bedsider and The National Campaign to Prevent Teen and Unplanned Pregnancy family;
  * To respond to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process, in response to a request for cooperation from law enforcement or another government agency, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims;
  * When we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, or as otherwise required by law;
  * To enforce our Terms of Use and other agreements, or otherwise protect or defend the rights or property of The National Campaign to Prevent Teen and Unplanned Pregnancy, its affiliates, or others, or the safety of the public;
  * In connection with a corporate transaction, such as a divestiture, merger, consolidation, or asset sale;
  * In aggregated or another non-personally identifiable form to third parties for various business purposes, including business analyses and advertising; and
  * As otherwise described to you at the point of collection or pursuant to your consent.

We do not sell or rent your personal information to anyone. 

### How you can delete or update your information

You can delete or update the personal information you have provided on Bedsider.org by contacting us at [info@bedsider.org](mailto:info@bedsider.org). 

Website visitors who don’t want their visit data reported by Google Analytics can install the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. This add-on instructs the Google Analytics JavaScript running on Bedsider (and other websites) to prohibit sending visit information to Google Analytics. Additionally, visitors that have installed the opt-out browser add-on are not exposed to [Content Experiments](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/1745147).

If you want to opt-out of Analytics for the web, visit the [Google Analytics opt-out page](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) and install the add-on for your browser. For more details on installing and uninstalling the add-on, please see the relevant help resources for your specific browser.

The Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on does not prevent data from being sent to the website itself or in other ways to web analytics services. 

### How we protect your information

We have implemented procedures to help protect the personal information that you provide to us. However, no method of transmitting or storing electronic data is ever completely secure, and we cannot guarantee that such information will never be accessed, used, or released in a manner that is inconsistent with this policy. 

### Children’s privacy

We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. Should we learn that a child under 13 has provided us with personal information, we will delete that information from our database. 

### A special word about public forums

Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online in public forums, that information can be collected and used by others. This includes any information that you choose to make publicly available. For this reason, we encourage users not to post any sensitive information, including personal information, in any public forums.

### External links

If any part of Bedsider.org links you to other websites, those websites do not operate under this Privacy Policy. We recommend that you examine the privacy statements posted on those other sites to understand their procedures for collecting, using, and disclosing personal information.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

We may update this Privacy Policy in the future. In the event that you provided an email address to use for account creation, we will notify you about material changes to this Privacy Policy by sending a notice to the e-mail address you provided to us or by placing a prominent notice on Bedsider.org.

### How you can contact us

If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, you may contact us at:

or by mail at:

The National Campaign to Prevent Teen and Unplanned Pregnancy 1776 Massachusetts Avenue, NW Suite 200 Washington, DC 20036 (tel) 202-478-8500 (fax) 202-478-8588

This privacy policy is effective as of November 1, 2009.

All rights reserved. Copyright © 2015. The National Campaign to Prevent Teen and Unplanned Pregnancy.
